Yujohn Nattrass

■ yujohn.natt@gmail.com
in linkedin.com/in/yujohn-nattrass

▼ yujohnnattrass.dev

Profile

I am a software engineer currently based in Queens, New York. I am a co-creator of Able, an open-source A/B testing framework for Jamstack applications using edge computing. I have multiple years of experience in the Ruby and Javascript ecosystems and am comfortable with AWS, Cloudflare, Docker, and Go.

Experience

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, *Able www.able-test.com* ☑

2021 - present

- Co-created Able, an open-source A/B testing framework for Jamstack applications using edge computing
- Designed, prototyped, and built Able using Cloudflare Workers, Cloudflare worker KV, and Amazon Web Services
- Led the design and development of AWS infrastructure to host Umami, an open-source analytics application, using ECS Fargate, ALB, and RDS resulting in a scalable solution
- Overcame challenges regarding an unsecured connection to our analytics application due to using HTTP by automating the process of enabling HTTPS, using Amazon Certificate Manager, Cloudflare API, AWS CDK, and AWS SDK
- Built the service that allows Able to inject analytic script tags in the HTML cached at the CDN with Cloudflare's HTMLRewrite API
- · Automated Able's infrastructure deployment with AWS CDK and Cloudflare API
- Authored Able's case study detailing the technical challenges we encountered

Software Engineer, *Self Employed*

2019 - 2021

- Request Bucket an application for collecting and inspecting HTTP/webhook requests. Built with Node, Express, and PostgreSQL
- Jello a project manager inspired by Trello built with Node, Express, MongoDB, and React/Redux
- Memory Cards a flashcard application built with Ruby, Sinatra, and PostgreSQL

Head Barista, Everbean Cafe ☑

2017 – 2021 | Surrey, Canada

• Planned and taught monthly coffee-related classes for the public.

Skills

Languages

Ruby, JavaScript, GoLang, SQL, HTML, CSS

Frameworks

React, Redux, Express, Sinatra, jQuery

Cloud

Cloudflare Workers, Cloudflare Worker KV, AWS CDK, AWS SDK, EC2, ECS, RDS, ALB, ACM, Docker, Digital Ocean Droplets, Heroku

Technologies

Git, Github, Linux, Node.js, HTTP, OOP, RESTful API, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, HandlebarsJS, vim

Certificates

AWS Certified Cloud Practitioner (expires on August 7, 2024)

Education

Software Engineering (Capstone), Launch School

A multi-year mastery-based software engineering curriculum.

2019 - 2021

Law Enforcement Studies Diploma,

Justice Institute of British Colombia

2014 – 2016 | New Westminster, Canada